naeyc.org 2019-04-06

# Privacy Statement | NAEYC

**Effective Date: May 25, 2018**

Your privacy is important to us.  This Privacy Statement describes the types of information the National Association for the Education of Young Children (“NAEYC” or “We”) collect from and about you when you visit any of our web properties (collectively the “Sites”) or use our mobile applications (each an “App”). The Sites and Apps are collectively the “Services.”  This Privacy Statement also explains how We may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of it. By using this Site, you agree to the data collection, use, disclosure and storage practices described in this Privacy Statement.

**INFORMATION COLLECTION**

In some countries, including in the European Economic Area, this information may be considered personal data under applicable data protection laws: 

  * **Information You Provide to Us**

We collect information from you when you choose to provide it to us.  This may include when you submit a membership application or otherwise join NAEYC, request information from us, register for a conference or other event, seek accreditation or otherwise participate in the accreditation process, purchase a product, create an account with us, sign up for newsletters or our email lists, use our Services, submit a rating or review, participate in a survey or promotion, or otherwise contact us.

The information we collect may include your name, address, email address, telephone number, mobile telephone number, geolocation information, photos or videos, user name and, if you are an NAEYC customer or member, credit/debit card number or other financial information.  For our accreditation process we may also collect information about your organization including but not limited to the organization’s program, staff and education information.  You may be required to provide certain information to create your account or to participate in the accreditation process.  If you use a third party service to login, link to us, or communicate with us (such as a social network or third party video chat), we may receive certain information about you from the third party based on your registration and privacy settings on those third party services. 

  * **Information We Automatically Collect and Cookie Policy**

We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to automatically collect certain information when you use our Services or interact with our emails and online or mobile advertisements.  For example, we may automatically collect certain non-personal information from you such as your mobile device identifier or MAC address, browser type, operating system, device model, software version, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, mobile or ISP carrier information, and the domain name from which you accessed the Services.  We also may collect information about your use of the Services including the date and time you access the Services, the areas or pages of the Services that you visit, the amount of time you spend using the Services, the number of times you return, whether you open forward or click-through emails and ads, and other usage data.  For more information on our use of cookies, click [here](https://www.naeyc.org/cookie-policy).

_Tracking Options, EEA and California Do Not Track Disclosures._   You may adjust your browser or operating system settings to limit this tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features on the Services or take full advantage of all of our offerings.  Check the “Help” menu of your browser or operating system to learn how to adjust your tracking settings or cookie preferences.  To learn more about the use of cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and your choices about not having this information used by certain Service Providers (defined below), please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).  On your mobile device, you can adjust your privacy and advertising settings to limit your tracking for advertising or control whether you receive more relevant advertising.  Note that our systems may not recognize Do Not Track headers or requests from some or all browsers. 

  * **Information Collected From Other Sources**

We may obtain information about you from other sources, including social networks that you use to connect with NAEYC.  This information may include name, user name, demographic information, updated address or contact information, interests, and publicly-observed data, such as from social media and online activity. 

  * **Combination of Information**

We may combine the information we receive from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Sites, Apps, as well as information collected offline or from third party sources to help us tailor our communications to you and to improve our Services.

**INFORMATION USE**

We may use the information we collect from and about you to: 

  * Respond to your inquiries, provide membership and member benefits, accreditation services and other services, fulfill orders, process payments and prevent transactional fraud, and contact and communicate with you; 
  * Develop new programs, products or services; 
  * Engage in policy initiatives to communicate with you and others to further our public policy and education goals; 
  * Provide you with customized content, targeted offers, and advertising on the Services, via email or text message, or on other sites or apps; 
  * Contact you with information, newsletters and promotional materials from NAEYC or on behalf of our partners and affiliates; 
  * Research, address problems, and improve the usage and operations of the Services; 
  * Protect the security or integrity of the Services and our business; and 
  * As described to you at the point of data collection. 

**INFORMATION SHARING**  
We may share the information we collect from and about you:  
(1) with selected third parties that we believe may provide member benefits, promotional materials, and goods and services that may be of interest to you;  
(2) among our local, state and regional affiliates and affiliate alliances (which may be selected as identified in your membership application);  
(3) to our Service Providers, if the disclosure will enable them to perform a business, professional or technical support function for us;  
(4) as necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of the NAEYC Terms of Use or of our rights or the rights of any third party;  
(5) to respond to judicial process or provide information to law enforcement or regulatory agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; and  
(6) as described to you at the point of collection.

Please contact your local, state or regional affiliate or affiliate alliance to manage your communications from such affiliates.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous non-personal information with third parties for their marketing or analytics uses.

We may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through the Services in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

**SERVICE PROVIDERS**  
We may contract with third parties to perform functions related to the Services (“Service Providers”).  Service Providers will have access to your personal information needed to perform their business functions, but may not use or share that personal information for other purposes.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**  
For California residents:  We may share your personal information with third parties and affiliated third parties (such as local, state and regional affiliates and affiliate alliances), some of which do not share the NAEYC name, for their direct marketing purposes.  As these third parties and this category of affiliated third parties are considered an _unaffiliated party_ under California law, you may opt-out of our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To opt out, please: 

  * Contact our [Member Services Department](https://members.naeyc.org/eweb/DynamicPage.aspx?Site=naeyc&WebKey=3b8a7703-992c-4d13-b741-95c3049f04cb)
  * Adjust your preferences through the [Member Login](https://www.naeyc.org/user/login?r=1&Site=NAEYC)

[​](https://www.naeyc.org/user/login?r=1&Site=NAEYC)We will continue to provide your information to local, state and regional affiliates and affiliate alliances identified in your membership application or account for the purpose of processing your membership in such affiliate and affiliate alliance programs.

**Your rights as a visitor from the European Economic area (EEA)**

If you are a European resident, our legal basis for collecting and using your personal data or information is to do so with your consent; where we need the personal data or information for performance of a contract, or where the collection and use is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect the personal information in question. If we collected your personal data or information with your consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time.

You also have the right to: 

  * Access your personal data or information; 
  * Delete, or request deletion of, your personal data or information; 
  * Object to or restrict processing of your personal information; 
  * Request portability of your personal information; 
  * Complain to your local data protection authority at any time; 
  * Object to automated decision making; and 
  * Update your personal data or information. 

To withdraw consent or exercise these rights, please: 

  * Contact our [Member Services Department](https://members.naeyc.org/eweb/DynamicPage.aspx?Site=naeyc&WebKey=3b8a7703-992c-4d13-b741-95c3049f04cb)
  * Adjust your preferences through the [Member Login](https://www.naeyc.org/user/login?r=1&Site=NAEYC)

Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

If we ask you to provide personal data to us to comply with a legal requirement or enter into a contract, we will inform you of this and let you know whether providing us with your personal data is required and if not, the consequences of not sharing your personal data with us.  

  Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our or a third party's legitimate interests and those interests are not already listed above (see "Information Use" section), we will let you know what those legitimate interests are.

**PUBLIC FORUMS**  
Any information you may disclose in ratings or review, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas of the Services, becomes public information.  Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas.

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**  
The Services may have links to third-party sites or applications, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own.  We are not responsible for the practices of such sites or applications.

**CHILDREN'S PRIVACY**  
Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Services to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen.

**DATA SECURITY**  
We have taken certain physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the information we collect from and about our customers and Services visitors and users. While we make every effort to help ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee our security measures.

**DATA STORAGE AND RETENTION**  
Your personal information is stored on servers in the United States.  You understand and agree that NAEYC may collect, use, disclose, and otherwise process the information you provide as described in this Privacy Statement even if you are from an area outside the United States.  Your personal information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities or to respond to judicial process in the United States. We will retain your personal information for as long as it is needed to provide you with the Services, or to fulfill any legal or contractual obligations we may have.

If you are a resident of the EEA: Your personal information will be transferred to and processed in the United States, which has data protection laws that are different than those in your country and may not be as protective. For more information on where and how long your personal data is stored, and for more information on your rights of erasure and portability, please contact ACA’s data protection officer at IT@naeyc.org.

  **ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL** **INFORMATION**  
If you have an account on our Services, you may sign in to your account and update your personal information contained in the account.

**IF YOU HAVE QUESTIONS**  
If you have any questions, requests or concerns about this Privacy Statement or the practices described herein, you may contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO) at: [IT@naeyc.org](mailto:IT@naeyc.org)

**REVISIONS TO THIS STATEMENT**  
We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Statement at any time. When we do, we will post the change(s) on the Sites or App.  If we change the Privacy Statement in a material way, we will provide appropriate notice to you. 

_Opting Out of Information Tracking_

Use the button below to opt out or opt in to information tracking.
